ulta.com 2019-06-24

# Privacy Policy | Ulta Beauty

## ULTA.com® Privacy Policy

Last Updated: 04/09/2019  
This website, Wi-Fi service, internet service, or mobile application ("Site") is owned and operated by Ulta Salon, Cosmetics & Fragrance, Inc. ("Ulta Beauty"). Ulta Beauty takes your privacy seriously. This Privacy Policy describes what information this Site gathers about you, how we use that information, and what steps we take to protect that information.

By using this Site, you consent to the terms of this Privacy Policy as well as the Site Terms & Conditions. Ulta Beauty may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. Please check back periodically for up-to-date information about our privacy practices.

### 1\. INFORMATION COLLECTION

This Site collects information about you to provide and improve our services, communicate offers that we believe will interest you, and to administer our business.

     _Information You Provide to Us_

    We collect personal information from you when you submit that information to us voluntarily. For example, we collect information from you when you:

  * place an order on the Site; 
  * create an account on the Site;
  * participate in our rewards program;
  * communicate with our customer service team online;
  * participate in an Ulta Beauty promotion, such as a sweepstakes or contest;
  * post a tagged photo or other content on a third party social network in response to our request; or
  * post a product review, question, answer, or other information on the Site; 

The personal information we collect may include the following: email address, mailing/billing address, phone number, payment card number, and other payment information. Collecting this information allows us to complete your order efficiently, to notify you of your order status, and provide personalized interactions. If we ask for such information from you, we will either tell you how we will use the information or we will use it in conformity with this Privacy Policy.  
We may use the personal information you provide to allow you to send message to your friends via this Site. When you use these features on our Site, you represent to us that you are entitled to use and give us your friend's name and contact information, including email address. 

     _Information from Third Party Sources_

    We may collect information about you from third parties. Such information may include demographic data (like the number of members of your household, age, and gender) and purchase preference information. We may use this information to supplement or update our records, improve the quality or personalization of our communications to you, and help prevent or detect fraud.

     _Automated Information Collection_

    We automatically receive and store certain types of information when you interact with our Site, our emails, and/or our online advertisements. This information helps us to make our Site work more efficiently, evaluate use of our Site, and support our website analytics and marketing campaigns. Here are some of the types of information we may automatically receive: 

  * Technical information like your internet protocol (IP) address, your device operating system and browser type, your referring website's address, and your clickstream through our Site 
  * Cookies that recognize you as you use or return to our Site. The cookies allow the Site to provide you a more continuous and personalized shopping experience. Cookies are small text files that a website or email saves to your browser and stores on your hard drive.
  * Web beacons that allow us to know what pages on our Site have been visited, what emails have been opened, and if our banner ads have been effective.

     _Cookies_

    Our Site uses cookies. Cookies are pieces of information that a website transfers to your computer's hard drive for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies to track your preferences and purchases as you navigate through our Site and to save you from having to re-enter information every time you visit our Site. By using cookies to track your visits, we can make your next shopping experience on our Site better. To search our Site and/or place an order, you need to have the cookies feature of your web browser turned on. We may also use technologies, such as our own cookies, to provide you with personalized online display advertising tailored to your interests. To opt out of our cookies used for this online advertising, [click here](http://dtmc.ulta.com/adinfo/choice/prod/?type=fpc&cid=2997&cname=Ulta&cmagic=a0b83c&clogo=2997.png&loc=us&lang=en-us "click here"). Most web browsers allow you to exercise control over cookies by deleting them, blocking them, or alerting you when a cookie file is stored. Please review your browser's instructions on these functions. If you choose to disable the cookies feature of your web browser, you may not be able to place an order or otherwise use some or all of the features provided on our Site. If you disable, block, or delete cookies, not all of the tracking described in this Privacy Policy will stop. 

     _Interest-Based Advertising_

    We collect personal information about users over time and across different websites when you use this Site. We also have third parties that collect personal information this way. For example, we may use one or more third-party online advertising networks to serve ads on our behalf on third party websites. The third-party ad network may collect information about your visits to our Site and your interaction with our online ads. For example, it may keep track of how many of our ads you saw before visiting our Site. This is primarily accomplished using technology such as cookies, action tags, web beacons, and/or GIF tags which are placed in various places within our Site and our online ads. 

    We may share information with third-party ad networks in an aggregate form to help us analyze and improve our Site and our online ads. The third-party ad networks may use information about your visit to our Site and other websites in order to provide you with ads about goods and services that may be of interest to you. For example, if you browse for information about mascara products on our Site or on third party websites, we or the online ad network may show you ads for mascara products. If you would like more information about this practice or the process of opting out of online ad networks, please visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>. If you opt-out of interest-based ads, you will still see ads on websites you visit, but those ads will not be based on your browsing behavior.

    Some browsers have a 'do not track' feature that lets you tell websites that you do not want to have your online activities tracked. These features are not yet uniform, so our Site is not currently designed to respond to those signals.

     _Wi-Fi Service, Mobile Applications and Website_

    When you download or use our in-store WiFi service, mobile application or mobile website, we may receive information about your location and your mobile device. This information may include the type of mobile device you use, the temporary or persistent unique device identifier (UDID) placed by us or our service providers, the unique identifier assigned by Ulta Beauty to your device, the IP address of your device, your mobile operating system, the type of mobile web browser you use, and data from the way you use our mobile application/website.

    Our in-store WiFi service/mobile application/website may also collect information about the location of your device. Your device should require you to provide permission before our in-store WiFi service/mobile application/website obtains location information from technologies like GPS, Wi-Fi, and/or cell towers. We and our service providers may use this information, along with other information submitted by you, to provide you with location-based services like local store information, search results, special offers, and other personalized content.

    Most mobile devices allow users to disable location services by using controls located in the device's settings menu. If you have questions about how to disable your device's location services, please contact your mobile service carrier or your device manufacturer. You may also stop collection of information by our mobile application by uninstalling the mobile application using the standard uninstall process available as part of your mobile device.

    If you uninstall our mobile application from your device, the unique Ulta Beauty identifier associated with your device may continue to be stored. If you re-install our mobile application on the same device, Ulta Beauty may be able to re-associate this identifier to your previous transactions.

    Your use of our in-store WiFi service is also subject to Ulta Beauty's WiFi Terms.

     _Social Media Widgets and Single Sign-On Services_

    This Site uses third party social media widgets such as buttons or similar mechanisms from Facebook,Twitter, Instagram, Pinterest, YouTube, and/or FourSquare. Such third party features may collect information about you, like your IP address and the page(s) you visit on the Site. They may also place cookies on your device. These social media widgets are either hosted by a third party or by our Site. Your interactions with those features are governed by the privacy policies of the third party social media networks that provide them.

     _Children Under 13 Years of Age_

    This Site is directed to adults, and does not knowingly collect personal information online from children under the age of 13 without prior parental consent. If you are the parent or guardian of a child under the age of 13, and you believe your child has provided personal information to our Site that you would like us to delete, please Contact Us

     _Virtual Beauty Information_

    The collection of "Virtual Beauty Information" is governed by the Virtual Beauty Try-On Additional Terms and Conditions in the Site [Terms & Conditions](https://www.ulta.com/ulta/common/user_agreement.jsp).

### 2\. INFORMATION USE, DISCLOSURE, AND SHARING

The information we collect on this Site may be used to fulfill your requests (such as product orders and responses to email questions), to support our core business functions (such as order fulfillment, internal business process management, authentication, loss and fraud prevention, and public safety functions), and to communicate with you about our product offers and promotions. When you create an account with us, we offer the opportunity to become a member of Ulta Beauty's Loyalty Program, so you may receive future discounts, gifts and Ulta Beauty e-mail. You can also sign up for our e-mail list by providing your e-mail address through our Site services or our affiliated retail stores.

To accomplish these purposes, we may combine information about you that we collect online, in our stores, via mobile applications, and from third party sources. We may also transfer or disclose your information within our corporate family of companies for these purposes.

We may make third party services, including third party applications, available to you on this Site. You may choose to allow us to share your information with those third party services. We require such third party services to give you notice of their privacy policy so you can review it before authorizing them to access your information.

We may disclose your personal information to identify you to anyone to whom you send messages via the Site. You may also disclose your own personal information on interactive services such as message boards, product reviews, question-and-answer pages, profile pages, and social network features offered by us or by third parties. Information you post or disclose through such interactive services may be available to the general public. Please exercise caution when deciding whether to disclose your personal information, location, or similar information via this Site.

We may disclose the information we collect about you (including personally identifiable information) to third parties to comply with applicable laws, regulations, and/or governmental requests. We may also disclose such information to verify or enforce compliance with our Terms & Conditions and this Privacy Policy, to process and fill your order, reduce credit risk, protect against fraud, protect against misuse or unauthorized use of our Site, or when we believe in good faith that the law requires such disclosure. We may also disclose such information to a successor entity in connection with a merger, consolidation, sale of assets or other corporate change affecting the Site.  
We may share personal information in connection with financial products or services related to our business such as private label credit cards. We may also share personal information in connection with co-branded product or service offerings. For example, when you apply for an Ulta Beauty credit card (co-branded or private label), we may share your personal information with our banking partners that issue the card.  
We may share the information collected on our Site with agents or contractors who provide support for our internal operations. Such entities may receive personally identifiable information to allow them to perform their duties, but they may not use that information for any other purpose. In some instances, we may share non-identifying and aggregate information collected on our Site with third parties, such as our merchandise vendors and service providers. 

The use, disclosure, and sharing of "Virtual Beauty Information" is governed by the Virtual Beauty Try-On Additional Terms and Conditions in the Site [Terms & Conditions](https://www.ulta.com/ulta/common/user_agreement.jsp).

### 3\. SECURING YOUR INFORMATION

Ulta Beauty works to protect your personal information and credit card detail when you shop with us online. We use Transport Layer Security (TLS) technology - the industry standard - to encrypt the personal information and credit card detail you provide during the order process.  
To ensure the security of your personal information, you should always provide that information over a secure connection. You can check the existence of a secure connection in one of two ways:  
    (1) Look at the URL in your web browser. Whenever you are connected to a secure server, that connection will be represented in the URL as "https," rather than "http."   
    (2) Look at your web browser. You have an SSL connection if you see a closed lock or a solid key. If you click on this image, a small pop-up window displaying website security information will appear.

We urge you to protect your own privacy. We recommend that you do not share your Site password(s) with anyone or in any unsolicited phone call or e-mail.

While our Site strives to ensure the integrity and security of our network and systems, Ulta Beauty cannot guarantee that our security measures will prevent third-party hackers from illegally obtaining this information. 

### 4\. PUBLIC FORUMS

Please remember that any information you may disclose in public areas of our Site or the Internet becomes public information. You should exercise caution when deciding to disclose personal information in these public areas.

### 5\. CONTACTING US

If you have any questions, please Contact Us by clicking the link.

### 6\. OPTING OUT

If you would like to stop receiving promotions, updates and/or special offers at any time, you may e-mail us at service@ulta.com with a statement requesting that you wish to cancel your Loyalty Club membership or that you would like to opt out of Ulta Beauty e-mail promotions, updates and special offers. Please allow sufficient time for your request to be processed. It may take up to 10 days to process an email opt-out request, and 4-6 weeks for other requests. 

     _Text Messages_

    Ulta Beauty may distribute mobile coupons and other text messages to devices of guests who request this information via an opt in request. To opt out of Ulta Beauty text messages, reply "stop" to text messages sent from 95637 (ULTA). This will opt you out of all Ulta Beauty text message campaigns from 95637 (ULTA).To opt out of text messages from 

_Ulta Beauty Messenger_

service, text STOP to (630) 410-9968. This will opt you out of all 

_Ulta Beauty Messenger_

text message campaigns from (630) 410-9968. 

     _Push Notifications_

    You may at any time opt out from further allowing Ulta Beauty to send you push notifications by adjusting the permissions in your mobile device.

     _Geo-Location_

    You may at any time opt out from further allowing Ulta Beauty to access location data by adjusting the permissions in your mobile device.

     _Uninstall the Ulta Beauty Mobile Application_

    You can stop all further collection of information by an Ulta Beauty mobile application by uninstalling the Ulta Beauty mobile application. You may use the standard uninstall process available as part of your mobile device or via the mobile application marketplace or network. 

    Note: If you uninstall the mobile application from your device, the Ulta Beauty unique identifier associated with your device will continue to be stored. If you re-install the application on the same device, Ulta Beauty will be able to re-associate this identifier to your previous transactions and activities.

Please be aware that, even if you opt out of receiving marketing communications from us, we may still contact you for transactional purposes. For example, we may contact you for order fulfillment purposes, customer service purposes, appointment reminders, or product recalls. 

### 7\. LINKS TO THIRD PARTY SITES

Our Site may include links to websites/applications that are owned or operated by third parties. Please note that this Privacy Policy does not cover the practices of those websites/applications. We encourage you to review the privacy policies on those websites/applications to see how they collect and use information. 

### 8\. HOW TO UPDATE YOUR INFORMATION

You can access or update your personal information in the following ways:  
(1) If you have created an account on our Site, you may enter and update your contact information after logging in to your account on our Site.

(2) You may also contact us by using the 'Contact Us' link above. Please include your current contact information, the information you are interested in accessing, and your requested changes. 

### 9\. YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS

If you are a California resident and an Ulta Beauty customer, you have the right to request information from us once per calendar year regarding the customer information we share with third parties for the third parties direct marketing purposes. To request this information, please send an email to [legal@ulta.com](mailto:legal@ulta.com) with 'Request for California Privacy Information' in the subject line and in the body of your message. We will provide the requested information to you via an email response. 

If you are a California resident under 18 years old and a registered user of the Site, you can request that we remove content or information that you have posted to our website or other online services. Fulfillment of the request may not ensure complete or comprehensive removal (e.g., if the content or information has been reposted by another user). To request removal of content or information, please Contact Us or call customer service at 866-983-8582.
